Marty Mann Papers
Marty Mann Papers
1943-1984
Mann, Marty, 1904-
30 linear ft.
Papers of the American advertising and public relations executive. Ms. Mann founded the National Council on Alcoholism in 1944, and served as its executive director until 1968. Collection includes correspondence (1944-1964); desk calendars (1946-1965); scrapbooks (1944-1962); manuscripts (1944-1948); speeches; and files of the National Council on Alcoholism, including executive minutes (1957-1965), board minutes (1954-1965), documentation on conferences and programs; and other organizational records.
149147
Biographical History
Margaret "Marty" Mann (1904-1980) was an American advertising and public relations executive and founder of the National Council on Alcoholism. Born into an upper middle class family in Chicago, Mann attended private schools, traveled extensively, and was a debutante. She married into a wealthy New Orleans family; when in her late twenties, due to financial reverses, she had to go to work, her social and family connections made it easy for her to launch a career in public relations.
Mann's "social" drinking, however, grew to the point where it endangered not only her business but her life, including at least one suicide attempt. In 1939 her psychiatrist, Dr. Harry Tiebout, gave her a manuscript of his book Alcoholics Anonymous, and persuaded her to attend her first AA meeting (at the time there were only two AA groups in the entire United States). Despite several relapses during her first year and a half, Mann succeeded in becoming sober by 1940 and, apart from a brief tumble nearly twenty years later, sober she remained for the rest of her life.
In 1945 Mann began working actively to eliminate the stigma and ignorance regarding alcoholism, particularly for women, and to encourage the "disease model" which viewed it as a medical/psychological problem rather than a moral failing. She helped start the Yale School of Alcohol Studies (now at Rutgers) and organized the National Committee for Education on Alcoholism (NCEA) which later became the National Council on Alcoholism (today the National Council on Alcoholism and Drug Dependence or NCADD). She was also in great demand as a public speaker, her personal experience making her particularly effective, and she was instrumental in educating the public that alcoholism is a serious but treatable disease.
Mann published her New Primer on Alcoholism in 1958. Although the National Council on Alcoholism had no formal relationship with Alcoholics Anonymous, Mann's willingness to admit her alcoholism and her successful experience with AA encouraged others to seek help, and Mann contributed the chapter "Women Suffer Too" to the 2d and 3rd editions of The Big Book of AA. In the 1950s Edward R. Murrow named her as one of the "Ten Greatest Living Americans." She died at home in 1980.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Marty Mann Papers includes correspondence, writing, printed material, and memorabilia. The collection is divided into 13 series.
Marty Mann files and Personal correspondence contain Mann's personal files and letters. Included here is a file of letters from author Carson McCullers, with whom Mann had an affair in 1950.
National Council of Alcoholism files (I) material includes articles of association, minutes, pamphlets, and other items relating to the organization's formation and early history. Additional NCA material may be found in the National Council of Alcoholism files (II) series below.
General files relate to organizations (National Budget Committee, Scientific Advisory Committee, Yale), tv and radio (radio spots "This I believe" and "Town meeting," proposed television series), and other topics. Included here are letters from families of alcoholics in more than forty states, in response to an article in the January 1963 Reader's Digest about Mann and her personal battle with alcoholism.
Writings contains galleys for and copies of Mann's New Primer on Alcoholism.
Notes contains desk calendars for nearly 20 years as well as personal notebooks and pocket calendars.
Pamphlets consists of printed material from the National Council on Alcoholism (brochures, leaflets, press kits), medical research reports, convention proceedings, and annual reports.
News clippings covers approximately ten years, and Scrapbooks of clippings approximately twenty years.
Memorabilia, donated at a later date, contains address books, awards and certificates, Marty Mann's obituaries, and material relating to her appearance on the Phil Donahue show.
National Council of Alcoholism files (II), donated at a later date, contains additional material on the NCA, including brochures about their various programs, annual reports, etc.
Book-related files, donated at a later date, contains correspondence with publishers, fan letters and royalty statements relating to Mann's books, including foreign editions.
Recordings includes speeches, remarks, workshops, and radio appearances by Marty Mann and others, as well as recordings of sessions at annual meetings and conferences of the NCA and other organizations and of memorial services for Ms. Mann. Also includes three film reels of short public service spots. Formats include films, reel tapes and phonodiscs. Much of this material has been digitized.
Other Formats Available
Many of the recordings in the collection have been digitized. Contact the repository listed above for more information.
Arrangement of the Collection
Within each series, material is ordered alphabetically. The series themselves are not in any particular order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Science and medicine; Women Authors; Gardner, Yvelin.; Mann, Marty, 1904-; McCullers, Carson, 1917-1967.; Oursler, Fulton, 1893-1952.; Peale, Norman Vincent, 1898-1993.; Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1913-1969.; Alcoholics Anonymous.; National Council on Alcoholism -- Records and correspondence.; Alcoholism.; Alcoholism -- Congresses.; Alcoholism counseling.; Public relations consultants -- United States.; 16mm (photographic film size); 35mm (photographic film size); Annual reports.; Audiotapes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Drafts (documents); Film reels.; Manuscripts for publication.; Memorabilia.; Minutes (administrative records); Pamphlets.; Phonograph records.; Proceedings.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Speeches (documents); Tape reels.; Public relations consultants.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to recordings requires advance notice to produce a use copy.
Acquisition Information
Majority of collection gift of Marty Mann, 1966-1968, 1984.
"Alcoholics Anonymous presents Marty Mann; San Francisco December, 11 1946" recordings, gift of Peter Desmier, 2014.
Inventory
- Marty Mann files
  - "About the House" CBS television show (Box 1)
  - Adelaide Hawley Program (Box 1)
  - "Alcoholics Can be Helped" [speech], March 9, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Articles other than Mrs. Mann's (Box 1)
  - Atlantic City Speech (Box 1)
  - Awards (Box 1)
    See also Memorabiia: Awards and certificates.
  - Biographies [of Mrs. Mann] (Box 1)
  - Conference programs (Box 1)
  - Detroit speech, sample for volunteer speakers (Box 1)
  - Files (Box 1)
  - High Watch Farm Notes (Box 1)
  - "Is There An Alcoholic Personality?" (Box 1)
  - "It's About Time" Flair article (Box 1)
  - Manuscript, "Alcoholic Dilemma" (Box 1)
  - Manuscript material for leaflets etc. (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts, 1946-1948[?]; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Margaret Allen Program CBS May 20 '49 (Box 2)
  - Martha Deane Program, 1946; 1950; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - "New Horizons in the Prevention of Alcoholism" address given by Mrs. Mann at Boston, Oct 4, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Nancy Craig Program (Box 2)
  - New Primer drafts (Box 2)
    See also Writings
  - Outgoing publicity procedures (Box 2)
  - Page, Mrs. H.M. (Box 2)
  - "Pastors' Resources in Dealing With Alcoholics" publication in Pastoral Psychology, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Primer on Alcoholism, 1951-1952; notes, clippings, correspondence, miscellaneous material (Box 2)
  - Publicity TIme Magazine photo offset (Box 2)
  - Quincy Howe television broadcast, May 1949 (Box 2)
  - Radio script (Drs. Shannon, Bacon, and Baird) Seattle, Wash., 1944 (Box 2)
  - Reader's Digest, 1961; 1963; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Recommendations for office reorganization (Spence) (Box 2)
  - Speaking dates records, March 25, 1947 to August 31, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Speeches (Box 2)
  - Station WWOD Lynchburg, VA (Box 2)
  - Surgery, Sep 1958 (Box 3)
  - "Tell Me, Doctor" (WJZ), Sept. 14, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Throat condition, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Walker Winslow (Box 3)
    Walker Winslow also corresponded under the name "Harold Maine." Items with the name Maine are found in various places in Ms. Mann's papers, but have not been collected here.
  - "We The People" CBS, May 1946 (Box 3)
  - "You and Alcohol" Columbia, B. C., Dec. 24, 1946 (Box 3)
- Personal correspondence
  - [General], 1944-1947; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - [General], 1948-1950; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - [General], 1951-1964; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Letterbook, 1964; three-ring binder with letters in sleeves (Box 5)
  - [General, unsorted], 1959-1969; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - [General], 1970; includes one folder of get-well cards related to an accident in 1970; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - [General], 1970; includes one folder of get-well cards related to an accident in 1970, and two labeled "Letters re: hip"; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - McCullers, Carson, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Robertson, Frances, 1959-1975 (Box 7)
- National Council of Alcoholism files (I), See also National Council of Alcoholism files (II), below.
  - Amicus Curiae (Box 8)
  - Articles of Association (Box 8)
  - Board Minutes (Extra Copies), 1954-1965 (Box 8)
  - By-laws (Proposed Changes), 1957 (Box 9)
  - Constitution and By-laws (Box 9)
  - Demonstration Plan (Box 9)
  - Executive Minutes (Extra Copies), 1957-1965 (Box 9)
  - "Facts on Alcoholism" (Box 9)
  - Facts and figures (Box 9)
  - Historical (Box 10)
  - Historical Papers (Box 10)
  - History (Box 10)
  - History, Dwight Anderson Library (Box 10)
  - Joint Meeting with Local Affiliates, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Local Brochures (Box 10)
  - Luncheon, St. Regis, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Minutes, letter, and reports, 1945-1948 (Box 10)
  - NCEA vs. Broun (Box 10)
  - New York State Registration, Charitable Agency, 1955-1956 (Box 10)
  - Objectives, 1955-1956 (Box 10)
  - Pamphlets on alcoholism (Box 10)
  - Pamphlets on alcoholism, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Policies and changes of policy reflected in meetings of board, 1944-1956 (Box 11)
  - U.S. Treasury Department (Form 990), 1945-1954 (Box 11)
  - Yale Severance (Box 11)
  - [Annual reports, 1945-1956 (Box 11)
  - [Annual reports, 1957-1967; 2 folders (Box 12)
- General files
  - Alcoholism pamphlets by other groups (Box 12)
  - Columbia Conference, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1946-1948; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Field Memo #10 NCC Pronouncement, Adams Brief, April 2, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Franklin Report, Planning Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 13)
  - Guide for the Clergy (Box 13)
  - Local Communities (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - National Budget Committee, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Programs, 1958-1965; 8 folders (Box 14)
  - Radio, "This I Believe" (Box 14)
  - Radio, "Town Meeting", 1955 (Box 14)
  - Reader's Digest letters
    - Filing [procedures] (Box 14)
    - Mrs. Mann's Responses to Reader's Digest Article (Box 14)
    - [Responses by state], Alabama to Arizona; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - [Responses by state], California -to New York; includes District of Columbia and separate file for New York City (Box 16)
    - [Responses by state], North Carolina to Wisconsin (Box 17)
    - Canada (Box 17)
    - Foreign & APO Military (Box 17)
  - Scientific Advisory Committee, Olson, Dr. Robert (Box 17)
  - Severance of NCA and Yale (Box 17)
  - Skid Row, regarding incidence of alcoholism among inhabitants of Skid Row (Box 17)
  - Television, Proposed Series, 1954 (Box 17)
  - Tuberculosis and alcoholism (Box 18)
  - Yale Clinic Budget (Box 18)
  - Yale (General), 1947-1955 (Box 18)
  - Yale Summer School Attendance, 1943-1947 (Box 18)
  - Yale Summer School, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Yale Summer School of Alcohol Studies Roster of Students 1948-1955 (Box 18)
  - Australia, New Zealand, 1961; 2 folders (Box 18)
- Writings
  - Marty Mann Answers Your Questions, See also Book-related correspondence; Marty Mann Answers Your Questions...: Drafts (above).
    - Typescript (Box 18)
    - Galleys (master proof and Marty Mann's copy) (Box 18)
  - New Primer on Alcoholism
    - Galleys (Box 19)
  - New Primer on Alcoholism
    - Galleys (Box 19)
    - Original typescript, unordered fragments, 12 folders (Box 19)
    - Original typescript, complete (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous notes, etc. (Box 19)
  - Pamphlets, miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - Published editions of books
    - Marty Mann Answers Your Questions About Drinking and Alcoholism, 1970; hardcover; with Mann's handwritten draft of bio for book jacket and typed draft (Box 20)
    - Marty Mann Answers Your Questions About Drinking and Alcoholism, 1981; soft cover (Box 20)
    - Primer on Alcoholism, Rinehart & Co., 1950; hardcover, no dust jacket; includes Mann's pencil corrections on some pages (Box 20)
    - Primer on Alcoholism, Rinehart & Co., 1950; two copies of hardcover with dust jacket; includes Mann's corrections on pages and on laid-in pieces of paper; 2 copies (Box 20)
    - Primer on Alcoholism, Rinehart & Co., 1950; hardcover with dust jacket, unmarked (Box 20)
    - Primer on Alcoholism, Victor Gollancz, London, 1950; British edition; hardcover with dust jacket; first, fourth and ninth printings; 3 volumes (Box 21)
    - New Primer on Alcoholism, Holt, Rinehart & Winston, 1958; hardcover with dust jacket; unmarked except that jacket is price-clipped (Box 21)
    - [New Primer...] Alkoholismi - mitä se on ja miten siitä voi toipua, Porvoo, Helsinki, 1958; Finnish edition; softcover (Box 21)
    - [New Primer...] Die Alkoholis, Afrikaanse Pers Boekhandel, Johannesburg, 1953; South African edition; hardcover with dust jacket (Box 21)
    - [New Primer...] Novo Concepto Sobre Alcoholismo, Comisino Sobre Alcoholismo, San José, 1969; Cost Rican edition; softcover with "SAMPLE" sticker across front (Box 21)
    - Wine Advisory Board Bibliography of Wine and Components, microfilmed; may be incomplete, missing part of A through part of I; 3 rolls (Box 21)
      Western Microfilm Co., San Francisco, California. Roll 1: from "Abashidze" to "Alcohol in Medicine"; Roll 2: from "Intravenous alcohol in obstetrical labor" to "Iron in wine"; Roll 3: from Iron in wine" to "Zinfandel grapes"
- Notes
  - Desk calendars, 1946-1949; 1952,; 1954,; 1956-1957; 8 folders (Box 22)
  - Desk calendars, 1958; 1960,; 1962,; 1964-1969; 9 folders (Box 23)
  - Desk calendars, 1970-1972; 1974-1977; 7 folders (Box 24)
  - Personal notebooks (Box 25)
  - Pocket calendars, 1947-1948 (Box 25)
  - Loose-leaf notebook (Box 25)
- Pamphlets
  - National Council on Alcoholism
    - Alcoholism Information Week Press Kit (Box 25)
    - Clergy (Box 25)
    - Doctors (Box 25)
    - Families (Box 25)
    - Hospitals (Box 25)
    - Industry (Box 26)
    - Introduction to Community Action (Box 26)
    - Nurses (Box 26)
    - Social Workers (Box 26)
    - Speakers (Box 26)
    - Students (Box 26)
    - Teachers (Box 26)
    - What is NCA? (Box 26)
  - Medical Research Reports, 2 volumes (Box 26)
  - General pamphlets (Box 27)
  - Annual reports, 1962-1966 (Box 27)
  - Proceedings and reports, 1953; 1955-1957; bound volumes or binders from various conferences and meetings; 7 volumes (Box 27)
  - Proceedings and reports, 1957-1959; 1961; bound volumes or binders from various conferences and meetings; 7 volumes (Box 28)
  - Treasurer's Reports 1944-1948 (Box 28)
- News clippings
  - Bermuda, 1953 (Box 29)
  - South Africa, 1951 (Box 29)
  - [General], 1953-1956; 7 folders (Box 29)
  - [General], 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Duplicates (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 30)
- Scrapbooks
  Titles are given as written on the album or binder. Assumed or inferred information is given in square brackets.
  - Local Committees on Alcoholism, 1954-1957 (Oversize 1)
  - Local Committees on Alcoholism, 1955-1956 (Oversize 2)
  - Marty Mann New Zealand Australia, February-March 1951 (Oversize 3)
  - Publicity, Primer on Alcoholism, 1950-1951 (Oversize 3)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. I, Oct 1944 - Dec 1944 (Oversize 4)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. II, Jan 1945 - Jul 1945 (Oversize 4)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. III, Aug 1945 - Jun 1946 (Oversize 5)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. IV, Apr 1946 - Nov 1946 (Oversize 5)
  - [National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. V], [1946-1947] (Oversize 6)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. VI, Feb 1947 - Aug 1947 (Oversize 6)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. VII, Sep 1947 - Dec 1947 (Oversize 7)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. VIII, Dec 1947 - Apr 1948 (Oversize 7)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. IX, Apr 1948 - Sep 1948 (Oversize 8)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. [X], Apr 1949 - May 1949 (Oversize 8)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. [XI], Jan 1950 - Jun 1952 (Oversize 11)
  - National Comm. For Education on Alcoholism Vol. [XII], 1952-1953 (Oversize 11)
  - National Council on Alcoholism, 1960 (Oversize 12)
  - [National Council on Alcoholism?] AIW Clippings, 1961; clippings related to Alcoholism Information Week (AIW) (Oversize 13)
  - National Council on Alcoholism / AIW Clippings, 1962; clippings related to Alcoholism Information Week (AIW) (Oversize 14)
  - National Council on Alcoholism Correspondence and Pamphlets, 1957 (Oversize 14)
  - [untitled], 1962 (Oversize 15)
- Memorabilia
  See also Scrapbooks, below.
  - Address and telephone books (Box 31)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 31)
    See also Marty Mann files: Awards (above).
  - Awards and certificates, oversize (Oversize 3)
  - "Book of the Month Club News" article, Oct. 1950 (Box 31)
  - Gold Key Award, April 1, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Obituaries, Marty Mann, 7/22/80 (Box 31)
  - Phil Donahue Show 1-4-71, materials sent, 1970-1971 (Box 31)
  - Phil Donahue Show 1-4-71, materials not sent, 1970-1971 (Box 31)
- National Council of Alcoholism files (II), See also National Council of Alcoholism files (I), above.
  - Annual Institute on the Homeless & Institutional Alcoholic, Fourth, 1959 (Box 32)
  - Annual Meeting of NCA, 1965; 1967; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Annual Reports, 1945-1954; 1962-1983; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Change in title from Executive Director to Founder-Consultant, 1967-1968 (Box 32)
  - "Comment", 1971-1974 (Box 32)
  - "Comment", 1975-1980 (Box 33)
  - Guest books, 1958-1978; 3 volumes (Box 33)
  - Newsletters, Spring 1967 - Fall 1969 (Box 33)
  - Papers and copy of final report (in binder), given to Jay Cross for "Program Goals and Priorities: Study Report", 1970 (Oversize 16)
  - Programs, 1966-1979; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Programs, 1980-1984 (Box 33)
  - Staff Orientation Kit, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Training courses (Box 34)
  - Yvelin Gardner papers (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
- Book-related files
  - Brandt & Brandt (Box 35)
  - Fan letters (Box 35)
  - Marty Mann Answers Your Questions...
    - Correspondence and contract (Box 35)
    - Drafts (Box 35)
      See also Writings: Marty Mann Answers Your Questions (below).
    - Holt, Rinehart & Winston (Box 35)
    - Lists and letters re: book (Box 35)
    - Press (Box 35)
    - Radio and television (Box 35)
    - Royalties (Box 35)
    - Statistical data, etc. (Box 35)
  - Primer on Alcoholism
    - Personal letters (Box 36)
    - (Afrikaans) Primer statements, etc. (Box 36)
    - (American) Primer statements (Box 36)
    - (British) Primer statements, etc. (Box 36)
    - (Finnish) Primer statements, etc. (Box 36)
    - (Foreign) Primer correspondence (Box 36)
    - (Japanese) Primer correspondence, etc. (Box 36)
    - Rinehart & Co. letters and bills (at back) (Box 36)
  - New Primer (& old)
    - Correspondence (Box 36)
- Recordings
  Three films are listed first, followed by audiorecordings in various formats, listed alphabetically by title or description.
  Access to recordings requires advance notice to produce a use copy.
  Many of the recordings in the collection have been digitized. Contact the repository listed above for more information.
  - 30-Second Film “Number One” XXGR0931, 04/08/1972; mann_m_188; Film: 35mm; color; sound; 00:00:30 (Box 37)
    Multi Media Mental Health. 30 Second public service spot. Note on box says “Produced by Grey-North Inc.”, label has letterhead of National Council on Alcoholism.
  - 60-Second Film “Number One” XXGR0861, mann_m_189; Film: 16mm; negative; sound; 00:01:00 (Box 37)
    Multi Media Mental Health. 60 Second public service spot. Note on box says “Produced by Grey-North Inc.”, label has letterhead of National Council on Alcoholism.
  - Alcoholism - Erin O’Brien. Spot No. 1 (Denove 7/30), mann_m_190; Film: 16mm; black and white; sound; 00:01:00 (Box 37)
    Alcoholism spots. From box: Client Erin O’Brien / 1 min. / Produced for National Council on Alcoholism / By Jack Denove Productions / Hollywood, Calif.
  - Alcoholics Anonymous presents Marty Mann, San Francisco, December 11, 1946; mann_m_179 through mann_m_186; 78 rpm phonodiscs 8 items
    Gift of Peter Desmier, 2014.
  - Alcoholism, the Community, and Industry, Marty Mann, Los Angeles, California, 03/14/1968; mann_m_068; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    "Mrs. Mann Luncheon honoring Tom Pike / Statler Hilton, Los Angeles, California. Talk, "Alcoholism, the Community, and Industry.""
  - "Alcoholism is a Disease," Mrs. Marty Mann, 06/06/1958; mann_m_093; 12" phonodisc
    Presentation by Marty Mann to the General Federation of Women's Clubs
  - Barry Farber Show, WOR, Marty Mann, New York, NY, 05/22/1963; mann_m_052; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From back of box]
    Program: Barry Farber Show M M Guest / Station: WOR (NY) / Time: 8:15-9:00 p.m.
    [From inside box]
    Barry Farber Show - Mrs. Mann / Side I
    Program starts out with question about Mrs. Mann's own experience during alcoholic years. Description of disease outlined. Examples from experience are used to develop explanations about alcohol and alcoholism. This is the most recent and best combination of Mrs. Mann's story and lecture ... if commercials could be cut out. "
  - Bob Dixon Radio Show - AIW [Alcohol Information], Mrs. Mann, 11/29/1961; mann_m_046; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From note in box]
    Bob Dixon Show - AIW / Mrs. Mann
    A question and answer show. These questions are heard in studio and come from public "live" by telephone. Questions are very poor. Mrs. Mann's answers are knowledgeable and warm. "
  - Commonwealth Club Address, Mrs. Marty Mann, San Francisco, California, 03/19/1965; mann_m_056; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From a copy of "The Commonwealth, Official Journal of the Commonwealth Club of California" inside the box]
    Friday March 19th, 12:10 p.m. Sheraton-Palace Hotel Rose Room
    "A Straight Look at the Alcoholic" / br Mrs. Marty Mann
    [sub heading] Founder and Executive Director, National Council on Alcoholism / World authority on alcoholism - herself a recovered alcoholic